<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<component type="desktop-application">
    <id>org.archivekeep.ArchiveKeep</id>
    <launchable type="desktop-id">org.archivekeep.ArchiveKeep.desktop</launchable>

    <name>ArchiveKeep</name>
    <summary>Archive files the easy way</summary>
    <description>
        <p>
            <em>DISCLAIMER:</em> This is an early release. The author already uses the software to fulfil own needs, but there's still a room for improvement and a potential to find undiscovered issues, bugs or edge-cases.
        </p>
        <p>Utility facilitating preservation of personal archive of files, replicated in multiple storages of own choice.</p>
        <p>The main focus is on preservation - keep identical copies while not performing any destructive operations, nor replication of corruption, nor other means of data loss.</p>
        <p>Features:</p>
        <ul>
            <li>Plain files - archived files aren't wrapped in custom format, and are readable with any application.</li>
            <li>Incremental synchronization - update offline and other storages incrementally, when they become available.</li>
            <li>Filesystem agnostic</li>
        </ul>
    </description>

    <screenshots>
        <screenshot type="default">
            <caption>Main window</caption>
            <image>https://archivekeep.org/generated_screenshots/desktop/main-window.png</image>
        </screenshot>
    </screenshots>

    <branding>
      <color type="primary" scheme_preference="light">#899cff</color>
      <color type="primary" scheme_preference="dark">#375fdc</color>
    </branding>

    <url type="homepage">https://archivekeep.org/</url>
    <url type="vcs-browser">https://github.com/archivekeep/archivekeep</url>
    <url type="bugtracker">https://github.com/archivekeep/archivekeep/issues</url>

    <provides>
        <binary>archivekeep-desktop</binary>
    </provides>

    <supports>
      <control>keyboard</control>
      <control>pointing</control>
    </supports>

    <recommends>
      <internet>always</internet>
    </recommends>

    <requires>
      <display_length compare="gt">360</display_length>
    </requires>

    <metadata_license>FSFAP</metadata_license>
    <project_license>GPL-3.0-or-later</project_license>

    <developer id="org.kravemir">
        <name>Miroslav Kravec</name>
    </developer>

    <content_rating type="oars-1.1" />

    <releases>
        <release version="0.6.0" date="2026-06-20">
            <description>
                <p>SQLite-backed index repository</p>
                <p>Added:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>filesystem repositories with SQLite-backed index,</li>
                    <li>detection of modified files and reindex dialog (SQLite-backed index only),</li>
                    <li>detection of deleted files and cleanup dialog (SQLite-backed index only),</li>
                    <li>action Add to other repository row actions.</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Changed:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>actions in other repository row display conditionally (only if available).</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Technical:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>upgraded Java to 21, Kotlin to 2.3.21, Gradle to 9.5.1, Android Gradle Plugin to 8.13.2, and Compose Multiplatform to 1.11.1.</li>
                    <li>upgraded UI and test libraries.</li>
                    <li>migrated application services creation to Metro DI.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="0.5.0" date="2026-01-14">
            <description>
                <p>E2E encryption</p>
                <p>Added:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>optional encryption of filesystem repositories,</li>
                    <li>optional encryption of S3 repositories,</li>
                    <li>error log to sync operations.</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Changed:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>license from AGPL to GPL,</li>
                    <li>errors in sync are skipped (and logged), and sync continues.</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="0.4.4" date="2025-11-30">
            <description>
                <p>Added:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>explanation of NotRoot error when adding a filesystem repository (related to #6),</li>
                    <li>repository deinitialization feature (related to #6).</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Fixed:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>watcher for mounted media not working if /run/media/ didn't exist at the start of the application (related to #6).</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="0.4.3" date="2025-06-17">
            <description>
                <p>Added:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>S3 integration - support S3 bucket as repository storage</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Changed:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>UI: add dialog for filesystem repository shows only close button on completion</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="0.4.2" date="2025-05-25">
            <description>
                <p>Added:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>progress info (percentage, name, speed, and estimate) about currently copied file:</li>
                    <li>in repo to repo sync dialogs,</li>
                    <li>in add &amp; push dialog.</li>
                    <li>estimate of time remaining to execute all sync operations</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Fixes:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>blinking or showing "1 uncommitted file" during copy operations</li>
                    <li>scrollbar missing in Desktop App</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Changes:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>Performance:</li>
                    <li>pause checking of local index status (uncommitted files) during save (copy) operation</li>
                    <li>index contents auto-refresh monitors only checksums dir (not all contents)</li>
                    <li>metadata information auto-refresh monitors only the file itself (not all - checksums and other things)</li>
                    <li>Other:</li>
                    <li>sync to filesystem (force data write to medium) for writes to repo every 25MB to get real values for write speed</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Technical:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>refactoring &amp; tests</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="0.4.1" date="2025-05-10">
            <description>
                <p>Changed:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>UI: make style more lighter by removing shadows, and adjust dimensions</li>
                    <li>logging: a bit cleaner logs</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="0.4.0" date="2025-04-29">
            <description>
                <p>Initial Android application, and UI improvements</p>
                <p>Added:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>UI: add connection status tag for storages in Storages view</li>
                    <li>UI: indicate disconnected status of repositories (reduce alpha, add text)</li>
                    <li>UI: responsive app navigation layout supporting mobile screens:</li>
                    <li>top bar &amp; drawer for small screens,</li>
                    <li>top &amp; bottom bar on narrow but tall screens,</li>
                    <li>rail bar for wide screens with low height,</li>
                    <li>top bar with embedded navigation for big screens.</li>
                    <li>UI: navigation bar instead of navigation rail on small width screens (window sizes)</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Changed:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>UI: move repository add actions to dropdown in app bar (or rail bar)</li>
                    <li>UI: improve look and feel of storages view</li>
                    <li>UI: show only available and connected storages in home view</li>
                    <li>UI: split storages based on type (local/external/online) in storages view</li>
                    <li>UI: less framed look of the application (make content flow behind window insets)</li>
                    <li>UI: remove welcome text from home page once setup for more efficient space use</li>
                    <li>UI: more compact dimensions for small window/screen sizes</li>
                    <li>UI: make dialogs utilize (more) screen space (dynamically based on items in many select)</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Fixed:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>repository shouldn't be added if init fails</li>
                    <li>repository addition not always detects correct filesystem (on new mounts) and mixes up different filesystems</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="0.3.3" date="2025-03-31">
            <description>
                <p>Added:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>feature: support index update for non-primary (filesystem) repositories of archives</li>
                    <li>UI: improve Upload/Download dialog: add progress summary, and error details in case of failure</li>
                    <li>UI: show execution indicator in dialogs</li>
                    <li>UI: show execution error (if failed) in dialogs</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Change:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>UI: unify and improve dialog control buttons for repository data operation dialogs</li>
                    <li>metadata: expand and improve AppStream metainfo (by @bragefuglseth)</li>
                </ul>
                <p>Fixed:</p>
                <ul>
                    <li>UI: crash with large amounts of items (to add/commit/push)</li>
                </ul>
            </description>
        </release>
        <release version="0.3.2" date="2025-03-25" />
        <release version="0.3.1" date="2025-03-22" />
        <release version="0.3.0" date="2025-03-21" />
        <release version="0.2.0" date="2025-02-05" />
    </releases>
</component>
